Ralph W. Seager Papers
Ralph W. Seager Papers
1954-2008
Seager, Ralph W.
6.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet from Penn Yan, New York (1911-2008). Correspondence (1955-1966); book manuscripts and galley proofs; notebooks; clippings, and photographs.
149573
Biographical History
Ralph W. Seager (1911-2008) was born in Geneva, New York an November 3, 1911. He graduated from Penn Yan Academy in 1928 and studied verse through a University of California extension course from 1950-1951. He also studied verse at the University of New Hampshire Writer's Conference in 1954. Since 1938, he has served as a postal clerk in Penn Yan and since 1960 he has been teaching creative verse writing at Keuka College. During World War II, he served in the South Pacific with the United States Navy.
Mr. Seager is the author of four books of verse; Songs from a Willow Whistle, Beyond the Green Gate, Christmas Chimes in Rhyme, and Cup, Flagon and Fountain. His poems appear frequently in national magazines and he is also the author of Sound of an Echo, a book of prose.
Mr. and Mrs. Seager had three sons. Mr. Seager resides in Penn Yan, NY.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ralph W. Seager Papers include biographical material, correspondence, manuscripts, galley proofs, photographs and published material. This collection also contains a number of unprocessed additions.
Correspondence includes incoming and outgoing correspondence. (See also: Subject Files).
Subject Files includes correspondence, manuscripts, galley proofs, photographs and published material arranged alphabetically by subject. It includes manuscripts of all of Mr. Seager's books as well as published copies of each book, correspondence, galley proofs and other material relating to their publication. Material covers the periods of 1954-1959 and 1961-1966.
Manuscripts consists of a manuscript of an article by Mr. Seager, a draft of an untitled poem, and a copy of a lecture. (See also: Subject Files).
Published Material consists of newspaper clippings, magazine articles by Mr. Seager, and a reprint of one of his poems. (See also: Subject Files). Inclusive Dates: 1954-1966, undated.
Additional material was added to the end of the collection on Feb 12 1968, and can be found in Box 6. Other material has been added since that has not yet been processed.
Arrangement of the Collection
The Ralph W. Seager Papers consist of four parts: Correspondence, Subject Files, Manuscripts, and Published Material. All items are arranged in alphabetical order according to subject matter or type of material (book, periodical, etc.)
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Seager, Ralph W.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Poets, American.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Editors A-Y, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Special assignments A-W, 1957; 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965; 1967 (Box 6)
- Subject Files
  - Awards and publicity, 1954-1959; 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Beyond the Green Gate, 1957-1961; 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Cup, Flagon, and Fountain, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - Christmas Chimes in Rhyme, 1961-1964; 1966 (Box 3)
    - Songs from a Willow Whistle, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
    - The Sound of an Echo (Box 4)
  - Christian Author's Guild Party Course, 1957-1961; 1965 (Box 4)
  - Conferences and workshops, 1958-1966 (Box 5)
  - Lists: publications (Box 5)
  - News release, Feb 1 1967 (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Seager, n.d. (Box 5, 6)
- Manuscripts
  - Article: "When is Poetry" (Box 5)
  - Draft of poem, untitled, n.d.; photocopy (Box 6)
  - Lecture: "The Poet Looks at Himself", 1963; photocopy (Box 6)
- Published Material
  - Article by Seager (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings about Seager, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Periodicals
    - The Christian Writer, Vol XIII, No. 1, Jan-Mar 1964 (Box 6)
    - Writer's Digest, Vol. 43, No. 10, Oct 1963 (Box 6)
  - Poem: "Wild Fire", 1967; reprint (Box 6)